I've seen death, I've seen...
我见过死亡 我见过...
...my friends, my men being killed.
我的朋友和弟兄们被杀害
and
并且...
This is...
不消几天
It doesn't take too many days of that and you change dramatically.
你整个人就会有很大的改变
We were hungry, we had no food...
我们很饥饿 没有食物
...we didn't have ammunition, it was cold, didn't have any clothes.
也没有弹药 天气严寒 我们却没有冬装穿
You couldn't build a fire.
连火也不能升
If you did, some crazy thing would shoot at you.
如果你升个火 就会有人向你疯狂射击
Every where you would look, you would see dead people.
不管是往哪里看 你都会看到死人
A dead soldier there, here. Ours, theirs.
到处都是死掉的士兵 有我们的人也有他们的
Then civilians besides. Dead animals.
还有死掉的平民 还有掉的牲畜
So, death was all over.
死亡到处可见
You don't have a chance when your friends go down to really take care of them as you might.
当你的战友倒下 就算你想也无法去救他们
And especially if you're under attack, moving, or whatever.
尤其在你遭到攻击...或者是冲锋的时候
I withstood it well but...
我当时忍受得住 但是...
...I had a lot of trouble in later life...
后来的人生却出现很大问题
...because...
因为...
...those events would come back and...
这些事情不断浮现眼前
You never forget them.
你永远也忘不掉
After holding the line at Bastogne...
在死守巴斯通防线后
...Easy Company was again called on to help push...
Ｅ连再次被征调
...the Germans back through the Bulge.
协助击退在突出部的德军
We were here this morning and then we came this way.
我们早上在这儿 然后我们由这里过来
Right, so, right here's gotta be the logging road...
对 所以这里应该有条伐木道路...
...coming into here, which means we get right there.
通到这里 就是说我们会走到这里
- Take it easy. - Stop crying, Malark...
- 轻一点! - 别叫 马拉其
...or I'll nail it to your head.
不然我把它钉到你头上
Good, it's made of wood.
你钉吧 反正那是颗木头
- Guarnere, move them out, let's go. - Yes, sir.
- 葛奈瑞 叫他们出发 我们走 - 是 长官
2nd Platoon, let's go!
第二排 我们出发了
I was glad to be out of my foxhole and moving again.
我很高兴能离开散兵坑 再度前进
Even if only to get warm.
就算只是为了取暖
Spread out. Keep your interval.
散开点 保持间距
E Company was sent to clear the Bois Jacques the woods near the town of Foy...
Ｅ连被派去搜索靠近佛伊镇的森林区
...in preparation for what we knew would be the eventual assault on Foy itself.
大家都知道这是为即将对佛伊的最后攻击做好准备
I see it, Buck. Watch for mines.
我看到了 巴克 小心地雷
During that 1,000 yard attack through the woods...
在穿越那片森林一千码距离的攻击行动中
...we encountered German machine gun fire and had a couple of casualties.
我们遭到德军零星机枪射击 并有少许伤亡
But, for the most part, met little resistance.
但大部分情况 只遇到小小的抵抗
Hoobler's run-in with the German officer on horseback...
胡伯勒遇到骑马的德国军官
...was the most dramatic moment of the day.
是这天最戏剧化的一刻
Halt!
站住!
Shit.
妈的
Thank you.
谢谢你
Hoobler had been talking about getting a Luger since Normandy.
胡伯勒从诺曼第登陆开始 就一直说要弄把鲁格枪
As we dug in, he went from foxhole to foxhole...
在我们挖散兵坑的时候 他一坑一坑告诉大家
...telling everyone how he'd finally got one.
他是怎样终于弄到一把
Down he goes, right out of the saddle, like a sack of potatoes.
他就从马鞍上像一袋马铃薯般掉下来
Outstanding accuracy on my part, if I do say so myself.
如果要我自己说 我还真够准
- Which you do. - Which I do.
- 你是很准 - 我是很准
Hell, Shifty, I think maybe I could have even given you a run for your money.
西福弟 我想我也许该让你打一发来赌一赌 对不?
No, I'm not a good shot.
不 我没那么准
Now, Dad, he was an excellent shot.
我爸是个超级射手 超水准
Excellent, I declare, he'd shoot the wings off a fly.
他可以把苍蝇的翅膀射掉
Lip, that German, what'd you think he was doing?
李普! 你想那德国人本来想干什么?
Probably a little recon.
可能是小规模侦察
He must have figured nobody would hear a horse.
他一定以为没人会听见马声
- I think he was trying to get outta Dodge. - Yeah.
- 我想他只是出来透气... - 是啊!
What happened to the horse?
那匹马怎样?
I don't know, probably still running. Hope he's okay.
不知道 可能还在跑 希望它没事
- You dug in? - Yeah.
- 你的坑挖好了吗? - 是的
Yeah, just thought I'd take a walk, shoot the shit.
只是想走一走 开几枪
You're a good shot, Hoob. Just glad you're on our side.
你是个好射手 胡伯勒 很高兴你是我们这一边
Thanks, Lip.
谢谢你 李普
- Hey, Lip? - Yeah.
李普
- Thanks for the help. - You got it, Shifty.
- 谢谢你的帮忙 - 没问题 西福弟
- Lip? - Yes.
- 李普? - 在
- You got a sec? - Yes, sir.
- 你有空吗? - 有 长官
Give him a hand.
去帮他忙
- Where's Dike? - He's around.
- 戴克去哪了? - 他在附近
Could you be more specific, Sergeant?
军士长 你可否再明确一点?
Not really, sir.
我不太确定 长官
I haven't seen him all day.
该死 我有一整天没看到他了
Didn't see him in the woods...
在穿越森林时我也没看到他
...and I have to figure out how we ended up.
而我得自己数出伤亡数字
- Two wounded. - Who?
- 两员受伤... - 是谁?
- Brown and Stevenson. - Goddamn it.
- 布朗跟史帝芬森... - 可恶!
Where's Dike? Where the hell is he? Where does he ever go?
戴克到底在哪? 我是说他到底会去哪?
I don't know, but I wish he'd stay there.
我不知道 可是我希望他永远别出现
Be nice if he took Lieutenant Shames with him.
他最好带着宣姆士少尉一起去
- Shut up, boys. - Shutting up, Sarge.
- 你们都给我闭嘴 - 闭嘴了 军士长
What the hell is that?
那是怎么回事?
- Patrol? - No, we would have heard.
- 巡逻队? - 不是 很远就会听见了
- One man, maybe a sniper. - That was no rifle.
- 一个人 也许是狙击手 - 那不是步枪的声音
What do you see, Shift?
你看到什么了 西福弟?
Nobody out there.
那里没人
Are you sure?
你确定吗?
Jesus, it's Hoob, he's shot.
是胡伯勒 他中枪了
- Sniper? - No, he shot himself.
- 狙击手吗? - 不 他打到自己
- Stupid. - Medic!
- 真蠢 发生什么事? - 医生!
- What happened? - Doc.
- 发生了什么事? - 医生
- Is he all right? - It's my fucking leg.
- 他还好吗? - 是我的腿
- He did what? - It just went off.
- 他怎么了? - 它突然走火
- What happened? - It just went off.
- 发生了什么事? - 它突然走火
Why is there a loaded gun in your pants?
你干嘛把上膛的枪放在裤子里?
- Buck, I wasn't touching it or nothing. - Goddamn it.
- 巴克 我碰都没碰 - 该死
- I wasn't touching it, I swear. - Medic!
- 我没有碰它 我发誓 - 医护兵!
Where are you hit, Hoob?
你伤到哪里 胡伯勒?
- Where are you hit? - In my leg.
- 你伤到哪里? - 我的腿
Hold on.
撑下去 胡伯勒
Now, don't look. It's gonna be fine. Don't worry about it. Come on.
你别看 胡伯 会没事的 别担心
It hurts like a son of a bitch. I think maybe I hit bone.
真他妈的痛啊! 我想我也许打到骨头了
Doc!
医生!
Don't worry about it. You'll be all right.
别担心 胡伯 会好的
Warm him up.
帮他保暖
Can you hear me?
你听到我吗 胡伯?
- Somebody keep him warm. - Sergeant.
- 谁来帮他保暖 - 军士长...
- Let me see it. - Hang in there.
- 让我看看 - 撑下去
Warm up some blankets or something for him.
要不要给他弄些毛毯什么的?
You're gonna be fine.
你会没事的
Keep talking to him.
继续跟他说话 别停
Okay, listen to me.
好 听我说
- Think it was a German leg? - Yeah, right.
- 你以为你的是德国腿吗? - 是的
You're gonna be fine.
你会没事的
Hold on. Perconte, put this across him.
坚持住 派康提 把这个替他裹上
Wrap him up.
给他保暖
Hang in there. Come on.
撑下去 胡伯
Lip. You said I was a great shot, right?
李普 你说我是个好射手吧?
You're a great shot. Come on, you jump out of planes.
你是个好射手 你是跳伞的
You're tough. He's still shivering.
你是个硬汉...撑着
It's not that bad at all, come on.
情况没那么糟 撑着
Stay with us. Hoob, take it easy.
坚持下去 胡伯 没事的
What are we gonna do?
我们该怎么办?
- How are we doing? - You're gonna be fine.
- 怎么办? - 会好的
We've gotta get him to an aid station.
我们得送他去救护站
- Hold on tight. - All right, let's get ready to move him.
- 抓紧 - 好 我们准备来搬他
Take it easy. Stay there, Hoob.
别紧张 撑下去 胡伯
Doc. Can't see anything
医生 我什么也看不见
Doc!
医生!
Jesus.
天啊
Perco, we need a jeep.
派康提 我们需要一辆吉普车
He was wearing so many clothes, we couldn't tell how bad he was bleeding.
他穿太多衣服了 无法判断他失血的状况
By the time we got him to the aid station, he was already dead.
等到我们把他送到救护站时 他早已断气了
The bullet cut the main artery in his leg, sir.
子弹切断他腿里的大动脉 长官
Hell, Lip.
见鬼 李普
It wouldn't have made a difference if you had known.
就算你们知道也没差别
Cut that main artery in the leg, that's it.
大动脉被切断 一切就完了
Yes, sir.
是 长官
I'm gonna go back and make sure the boys are all dug in, sir.
我要回去确定兄弟们都挖好散兵坑了
Lip.
李普
Where's Dike?
戴克在哪里?
You wanna see him, sir?
您要见他吗 长官?
No, I just would have expected to get this kind of news from him.
不是 我只是以为这种事该是他来向我报告
I was there, sir.
我当时在场 长官
I figured it might as well be me.
我想还是由我向您报告
"Where's Dike?"
"戴克在哪里? "
I probably heard that question 1,000 times.
我可能已听过这个问题有一千遍
I probably asked it a few times myself.
我自己也可能问过几遍
There were long stretches where we didn't know where Lieutenant Dike was.
曾有几次很长时间我们不知道戴克中尉的去向
He'd disappear, go off on these walks for hours at a time.
他会消失 一次巡视就好几个小时
Wouldn't have been so bad if he was just one of the guys in the company...
他如果只是连上兄弟之一 情况不会那么糟
...but Lieutenant Dike was supposed to be leading the company.
戴克中尉应该是领导全连的人
Captain Winters was a CO we could all respect.
温特斯上尉曾是全连景仰的连长
Moose Heyliger probably would have done a good job...
穆斯海力格可能也会有好表现
...but before we got a chance to find out, he was accidentally shot by a sentry.
可是在有机会看到之前 他被哨兵开枪误伤
Then came Norman Dike.
接着诺曼戴克来了
I want tight security around the company CP, Lieutenant Shames, that understood?
我要连指挥部四周严密戒护 宣姆士少尉 了解吗?
Dike wasn't a bad leader because he made bad decisions.
戴克之所以领导不佳并非他做出错误决定
He was a bad leader because he made no decisions.
而是因为他不做决定
Now, Battalion S-3 is planning a move.
营作战部正在计划一次行动
So, I will probably be called away regularly.
所以我可能常会被叫去开会
- Are there any questions? - Yeah.
- 有什么问题吗? - 有
What's the formation you want us to go for?
你要我们以什么队形前进?
At present, as per usual, but I'll clarify that with you at a later time, Lieutenant Compton.
跟平常一样 我待会再跟你确认 康普顿中尉
Yes, sir.
是 长官
All right, I gotta make a call.
好 我得去打个电话
Let's move it out.
我们出发了
Dike was the favorite of somebody at Division.
戴克是师部某人的爱将
He'd been sent down to E Company to get some combat experience.
他被调来Ｅ连 吸取作战经验
Sometimes we got the feeling E Company was an annoyance to him.
有时我们觉得他对带领Ｅ连很感冒
Something he had to get through before he could continue his march up the ladder.
是一件在他官阶更上层楼前必要的不愉快经历
I'm telling you boys, we're screwed.
我告诉你 弟兄们 我们完蛋了
If you ask me, I'm glad Dike's never around.
如果你问我 我会高兴戴克中尉从来不出现
You know what?
你知道吗?
We're doing all right, even with Foxhole Norman.
就算跟着"散兵坑诺曼"也不会这么糟
Yeah, we're doing all right. We're doing all right now.
对 唐 我们现在还好
If you noticed, there's a little town down the hill.
如果你留意 在那山脚下有个小村落
In that town are these guys, and these guys are called Germans.
在村里有一群人 叫做德国人
- And these Germans got tanks. - I know.
- 并且这些德国人有坦克车 - 我知道
Yeah.
对
And our side's gonna wanna go into that town.
而我方想要进入那个小镇
Guess who they're gonna want to go knocking on the goddamn doors.
你猜他们会要谁去敲那扇该死的门?
I know, Bill, it's me you're talking to here.
我知道 比尔 你是在跟我说话
Jesus Christ, we've gotta do all this with a CO...
老天 我们得跟一个...
...who's got his head so far up his ass that lump in his throat is his goddamn nose.
完全没进入状况的连长去执行任务
- Hey First Sergeant. - Boys.
- 嘿 军士长 - 弟兄们
- Sarge. - Lip.
- 中士 - 李普
Muck...
穆克...
- ...what's the word? - You know.
- 情况如何? - 你知道的...
Sitting around, freezing our ass off.
坐到屁股冻烂
- Singing Dike's praises. - Yeah.
- 唱着赞美戴克的歌 - 对...
Lieutenant Dike.
戴克中尉
I'll tell you...
我告诉你
...I wouldn't wanna be a replacement officer coming in here...
要是我的话 我不会愿意当个替补军官
...getting thrown in with a group of guys who've known each other for two years.
就这么被丢进一群彼此已经认识两年的弟兄们里
They've been in combat together since Normandy.
从诺曼第就一起作战的兄弟
You're supposed to just show up and lead them?
就这么突然出现 带领他们
How's a guy do that?
有谁能办得到?
How could anyone really hope to gain the respect of the toughest...
谁能期待在一群欧洲战区中
...most professional most dedicated sons of bitches in the entire ETO?
最骁勇善战的战士中得到尊敬?
So, if you ask me, a guy'd have to march off to Berlin...
所以如果你问我这样的人必须行军到柏林
...and come back with Hitler's moustache or something.
然后带着希特勒的胡子回来
Anyway, listen.
总之 听着
You guys, don't worry about Dike.
你们别再担心戴克了
- All right? - Yeah.
- 好吗? - 好
We all do our jobs, everything will be fine.
我们做好份内的工作 一切都会没事的
- See you, Sarge. - Yeah, boy.
- 一会儿见 军士长 - 好 小子
I don't know if I believed any of that...
我也不知道自己信不信这些话
...but as Company First Sergeant it was my job...
但身为连队军士长 这是我的工作
...not to protect Dike...
不是去保护戴克
...but to protect the integrity of the company.
而是去保护连队的完整
You know what Dike's problem is, don't you?
你知道戴克的毛病在哪里吧?
He's just another one of those arrogant, rich jerks from Yale.
他只是另一个来自耶鲁的有钱自大狂
God, not another one of those.
天啊 别又来一个了
Division's not gonna let me replace him just 'cause I got a bad feeling about him.
师部不会因为我对他的感觉不好而撤换他
Even if they would, who'd I put in his place?
就算他们会 我该找谁替他?
Shames?
宣姆士吗?
Do not ever talk when I'm talking, you got that?
我讲话时你们给我闭嘴
He's seen too many movies. Thinks he has to yell all the time.
宣姆士看了太多战争电影 以为他得一直用吼
Both of you little crapheads did not listen to a word I said during that briefing, did you?
你们两个猪头在简报时都没注意听 对吧?
Or Peacock?
或是皮卡克?
God bless him, no one tries harder but he's not cut out to take men into combat.
老天保佑他 他真的很努力 但他不适合带兵作战
I'm not gonna make him Company CO when I don't want him as a platoon leader.
我连排长都不想让他干 更不会让他当上连长
What about Compton?
康普顿呢?
He's the only real choice.
巴克是目前唯一的选择
Buck's a real combat leader, but, you know...
巴克是个真正的战斗领导 可是你知道
I want Easy Company to have at least one experienced platoon leader.
我希望Ｅ连至少要有一个有经验的排长
Not that it matters anyway 'cause I can't get rid of Dike.
这些考虑都无所谓 反正我也甩不掉戴克
Well...
嗯...
...we all know who you'd like to have running Easy.
我们都知道你要谁来带领Ｅ连
Trouble is it's not your job any more.
问题是这不是你的工作了 迪克
We've gotta find somebody.
工作总得有人去做
We all agreed Buck Compton would've been the best choice to run Easy...
我们都同意巴克康普顿会是带领Ｅ连的最佳人选
...if Winters had been able to get rid of Dike.
如果温特斯能够甩掉戴克的话
But, to be honest...
可是老实说
...Buck wasn't the same soldier he'd been before he got shot in Holland.
巴克已经不是以前那个在荷兰中弹前那样的战士了
He was more serious somehow.
他现在变得比较严肃
He had a goddamn Luger in his pants.
他竟然把鲁格枪放在裤子里
Jesus. Dear God.
老天爷
Don't you two do something stupid like that, all right?
你们俩可别给我做出那样的傻事 知道吗?
- Try not to, Buck. - I mean it.
- 我尽量 巴克 - 我是认真的
And you, Wild Bill...
还有你 疯狂比尔
...I've invested too much goddamn time...
我可在你身上花很多时间
...shaping you into something useful.
把你塑造成可用之材
Do something crazy, get yourself knocked out of this thing...
你要是做出什么疯狂的举动 把你自己给撂倒了
I know, you'll kill me.
我知道 你会把我杀了
Even if you're dead, I'll still kill you.
就算是你死了 我还是要杀你
I'll see you guys later. I'm gonna check on the other guys.
我们待会见 我要去看看别的兄弟
Crazy Joe McCloskey.
疯子"乔麦克罗斯基"
What?
什么?
This guy used to hang at the front of Delancey's and just...
这家伙以前常在迪兰西防线走动
...you know, just stare at people.
盯着大家看
Yeah, I know who Crazy Joe McCloskey is.
我知道谁是疯子"乔麦克罗斯基"
What the hell's that got to do with anything?
这跟什么扯得上关系 贝比?
Buck kind of reminds me of him now.
巴克有点让我联想到他
- What? - Ever since he got shot in Holland...
- 什么? - 你也知道他在荷兰受伤后
Wait.
等等...
What, are you saying he's nuts?
你说他是个疯子?
'Cause Crazy Joe McCloskey was fucking nuts.
因为疯子"乔麦克罗斯基"是神经病
- That's why they called him Crazy Joe. - No, I'm not saying he's nuts. I'm just...
- 他们叫他疯子乔... - 不 不是说他是疯子 只是...
What are you saying?
什么? 你要说什么?
Forget it.
算了!
- What? - Forget it.
- 什么? - 算了!
Come on, you've seen him, Bill.
拜托 你看过他那样 比尔
He's all wound up like a spring.
他整个人紧张得像个弹簧似的
He's fine.
他很好
It wasn't getting shot that got him, it was being in that hospital.
他不是因受伤才变成这样 是因为待过医院
I've been there, okay?
我住过那里
It ain't pretty. Yeah.
那里可不好过
Once he was up and moving around, he was his old self again.
你也看到了 他一旦动起来还是跟以前一样
I'm telling you, Buck Compton's fine.
我告诉你 巴克康普顿好得很
- I'm serious. - Sure thing, Buck, nothing stupid.
- 我是认真的 - 当然 巴克 不做傻事
- We got it, right? - We got it.
- 我们知道了 对吧? - 我们知道了!
All right. George?
很好! 乔治?
Yeah.
很好
Nothing stupid, Buck.
不做傻事 巴克
"Don't do anything stupid"? Who the hell's he talking to?
"不做傻事"? 他在跟谁说话?
Bunch of morons who volunteered to jump out of a perfectly good airplane.
一群白痴志愿从好好的飞机里向下跳
- Can you get any more stupid than that? - Probably not.
- 有谁会比这样还傻? - 或许没有
Right.
对
- I swum across the Niagara once. - Yeah.
- 我曾经游泳横渡尼亚加拉瀑布... - 是吗?
I swear.
我发誓
On a bet.
要不要打赌?
What, in a barrel?
怎么游 在桶子里?
No.
不是
I didn't go over the Falls, George. I swam across the river.
我不是去跳瀑布 乔治 我是游泳横渡河水
Ten miles up from the Falls. I tell you, that current is damn strong.
是在瀑布上游十里的地方 我跟你说 那水流可真强
Yeah.
对
Must have carried me two miles downstream before I got across.
我至少向下游被推了两里才游上对岸
But, I got across.
毕竟 我总算游过去了
Now, personally, I didn't think it was all that stupid but...
我个人并不觉得那有什么愚蠢 可是...
...my mom, my sister, Ruth...
我妈妈 我姐茹丝
...they gave me all kinds of hell.
可把我骂得狗血淋头
- Yeah, I bet, Muck. - So did Faye.
- 我相信 穆克 - 费依也是一样
- Sweet Faye Tanner. - Shut it, George.
- 甜美的费依云娜... - 闭嘴 乔治
Well, they had a point. You're an idiot.
她们骂得有理 你是个白痴!
I heard about Hoobler.
我听说胡伯勒的事了
Shame.
真可惜
Yes, sir.
是 长官
- That the Luger? - Yes, it is.
- 就是那把鲁格枪? - 是 就是这把
What are you gonna do with it?
你要怎么处理它?
I don't know yet.
我还不知道
Where you from, Lipton? Where'd you grow up?
你是从哪来的 李普? 你在哪长大?
Huntington, West Virginia.
西维吉尼亚的亨庭顿
- Huntington? - Yes, sir.
- 亨庭顿? - 是 长官
I don't know it.
我没听过
What kind of work did you do there?
你在那里从事什么行业?
My brother and I helped my mom run a boarding house.
我和我弟帮我妈经营一间民宿
And your father?
你父亲呢?
He was killed when I was 10, sir.
他在我十岁时死了 长官
Automobile accident.
出了一场车祸
That's sad.
真令人难过
So, what made you decide to join the Paratroopers?
是什么让你决定加入空降部队?
I read an article about paratroopers in Life magazine.
我在"生活"杂志上看到一篇关于伞兵的文章
Talked about the training, how hard it was.
它提到训练有多难
Said if you want to make it as a paratrooper you had to be the best.
又说要成为伞兵最优秀的
And I wanted to fight with the best, sir.
而我想和最优秀的人并肩作战 长官
You miss it?
你会想吗?
Miss what?
想什么?
Huntington.
亨庭顿
Honestly, sir, I try not to think about it that much.
老实说 长官 我尽量不去想那么多
Where are you from...
您是哪里人 长...?
Captain Nixon, sir.
尼克森上尉?
- Captain Nixon, sir. - What?
- 尼克森上尉 - 什么事?
Good morning, sir, sorry to disturb you. This came from Division.
早安 长官 抱歉打扰你 这是从师部来的
All right.
好了
- Morning. - Eviction notice? - Not quite.
- 早安! - 逐客令吗? - 不是
But I think this will help with your leadership problem.
可是我想我有办法能帮你解决部队领导的问题
- Dike's being transferred? - No, I can't help you with that...
- 戴克被调职了吗? - 没有 那个我帮不上忙
...but Division has decided to pluck one officer...
可是师部决定要从每个团
...from each regiment that served in the heroic defense of Bastogne...
选出一位参与巴斯通之役的军官
...send him back to the States on a 30-day furlough.
停职三十天送他回美国
Get him out banging the drum for the war bond drive, that kind of thing.
去为战争公债做宣传之类的事
It turns out I've been plucked.
结果是我被选中
Hey
嘿...
- That's fantastic, Lew, good for you. - Thank you.
- 那真不错 是件好事 - 谢谢你!
How in the world does your leaving help me?
你离开怎么会帮助我?
It doesn't, I'm not going.
是没有 我不想去
I've already seen the States, grew up there. That's why I came to Europe.
我去过美国 我在那里长大 所以我才来欧洲
Just wish they'd told me there was a war on.
我只希望他们早点告诉我这里在打仗
Anyway, the point is, this thing's wasted on me.
不管怎样 重点是这件事对我是种浪费
But, I'm sure we can find an officer somewhere...
可是我相信能在营里找到军官
...in this battalion who could use a long trip home.
来享用这个回家的长假
Congratulations, Lieutenant Peacock.
恭喜你 皮卡克少尉
I can't think of anybody who deserves this more.
我想不出有谁比你更够格的了
Thanks.
谢谢
I'm really glad that you're going home. Okay.
我真高兴你要回家了 是啊
Best news I've heard in weeks. Hell of a guy.
这是我这周听到最棒的消息 好人一个
Thanks, guys. It really means a lot, you know?
谢谢你们 这对我真的是意义重大
Get out of here.
少来了
Three cheers for Lieutenant Peacock. Hip hip hooray.
为皮卡克少尉欢呼三次 预备 加油!
If they come by here, you all remember to smile for the camera.
如果他们来这里 要记得对镜头微笑
Got to keep the morale up for them folks back home.
我们得让家乡的人士气高昂
Why?
为什么?
Damned if I know.
我哪知道!
All right, Nix, what have they got waiting for us in Foy?
好了 尼克 敌军在佛伊准备了些什么在等我们?
At least one company from the 10th Panzer grenadiers dug in here.
至少有第十装甲掷弹兵师的一个连在此驻扎
They've also got at least one 88 although we haven't been able to spot it yet.
虽然还无法观测到 但至少有一门88毫米炮
- How about armor? - As of last night, three Tigers.
- 装甲车辆呢? - 到昨晚为止有三辆虎式坦克
- Would you excuse me for a moment, sir? - Yeah.
- 长官 我暂时离开一下可以吗? - 好的
How do I feel about being rescued by Patton?
我对于被巴顿援救有何感想?
I'd feel pretty peachy about it, if it wasn't for one thing...
这么说吧 我觉得还不错 除了一件事以外
...we didn't need to be fucking rescued by Patton.
那就是我们根本不需要巴顿的援救
You got that?
你懂吗?
Joe. Excuse us for a moment.
乔 我们失陪一下
- Sorry, sir. - Sorry about what?
- 抱歉 长官 - 为什么抱歉?
Patton?
关于巴顿?
I couldn't agree more.
我完全同意你
- What are you doing here? - I wanna head back to the line, sir.
- 你在这里干什么? - 我想上战场 长官
You don't have to do that. Get yourself back to the aid station. Heal up.
你不必这样做 快回救护站去疗伤
I'd really like to head back with the fellas, sir.
我真的很想跟兄弟们在一起 长官
All right, then go.
好 你去吧
Thank you, sir.
谢谢你 长官
Joe Toye had been at the aid station for three days...
乔托伊在救护站待了三天
...and everybody was glad to have him back.
每个人都很高兴他能回来
Especially Bill Guarnere.
特别是比尔葛奈瑞
- Joe. - Bill.
- 乔? - 比尔!
- Good to see you, pal. - You, too.
- 见到你很高兴 - 我也是
What the hell you doing back here?
你回来干嘛?
To make sure you're on top of things.
回来看你们是否一切顺利
I'm on top of things. Tied me own boots once last week.
我可很顺利 上星期还自己注射毒品
All by meself. Fellas, look who I found.
完全只靠自己 各位 看看我找到谁
- Joe Toye, back for more. - How are you, Joe?
- 乔托伊 再回来受罪! - 你好吗 乔?
Yeah, doing pretty good. Escaped from the aid station.
蛮好 从救护站逃出来了
- Where'd you get hit? - What's that?
- 你是哪里受伤? - 是谁在说话?
- It's Webb. Replacement. - Really?
- 是新兵韦伯 - 真的?
Thought it was some guy I've known for two years and I forgot his face.
我以为是我认识了两年的兄弟 可是忘了长相
Joe got hit in the arm. New Year's Eve gift from a luftwaffe.
乔伤在手臂 是德国空军的新年贺礼
- A lot of you guys been injured? - It's called wounded, peanut.
- 你们很多人都受过伤吧? - 这是叫做负伤 小子!
Injured's when you fall out of a tree or something.
从树上掉下来的才叫受伤
Don't worry, there's enough crap flying around here.
别担心 这里到处都有东西乱飞
You're bound to get dinged sometime.
你迟早都会被打中的
Almost every single one of these guys has been hit at least once.
这里几乎每个人都至少被打中过一次
Except for Alley, he's a two-timer.
艾利除外 他中了两次
He landed on broken glass in Normandy...
他在诺曼第降落在碎玻璃上
...and got peppered by a potato masher in Holland.
又在荷兰被马铃薯搅碎机打伤
You'll find out, son.
你会明白的 小子
Now, Bull, he got a piece of exploding tank in Holland.
再来是大牛 他在荷兰被爆炸的坦克碎片击中
And George Luz here has never been hit.
还有这里的乔治鲁兹 从来没被打中过
- You're one lucky bastard. - Takes one to know one, Skip.
- 你这个幸运的混蛋! - 彼此彼此 "史基普"
- Consider us blessed. - Now, Liebgott, the skinny little guy...
- 算我俩老天保佑 - 再来是李高特 那瘦小的家伙?
...he got pinged in the neck in Holland.
他在荷兰时脖子中弹
Right next to him, that other skinny guy, that's Popeye.
在他旁边另一个瘦小的家伙
He got shot in his scrawny little butt in Normandy.
他在诺曼第时瘦小的屁股中了弹
And Buck got shot in his rather large butt in Holland.
还有...巴克的大屁股在荷兰中弹
Yeah, kind of an Easy Company tradition, getting shot in the ass.
对 屁股中弹像是Ｅ连的传统
Even First Sergeant Lipton over there...
那边的李普军士长...
...he got a couple of pieces of a tank shell burst at Carentan.
在卡灵顿被几片坦克炮弹碎片击中
One chunk in the face.
一片括进脸里
Another chunk almost took off his nuts.
另一片差点毁了他的蛋蛋
- How are those nuts, Sarge? - Doing fine, Bill.
- 你的蛋蛋还好吗 军士长? - 都很好 比尔
Nice of you to ask.
谢谢你的关心
On the afternoon of January 3...
1月3日下午
...most of E Company headed back to our old position in the woods overlooking Foy.
Ｅ连大部分的人回到能俯瞰佛伊的森林旧阵地里
A few men remained in the Bois Jacques attached to D Company to hold the main line of resistance.
一些人留在与Ｄ连比邻的波扎克守住主要防线
Good luck, ladies.
祝好运 女士们
Been nice knowing you.
很高兴认识你
Wouldn't drink too much if I were you.
我如果是你就不会喝那么多
- Be careful if he offers you a cigarette. - What are they talking about?
- 如果他请你抽烟可要小心点... - 他们在说些什么?
- If who offers us a cigarette? - Speirs.
- 如果谁请我们抽烟? - 史毕尔
- Who? - Lieutenant Speirs.
- 是谁? - 史毕尔中尉
Lieutenant Ronald Speirs was one of the platoon leaders in D Company.
隆纳得·史毕尔中尉是Ｄ连的排长
He was already a legend.
他已经是个传奇人物
The stories about Speirs are probably all bullshit anyway.
有关于史毕尔的故事 可能都是胡说八道
What stories?
什么故事?
Supposedly Speirs shot one of his own men for being drunk.
有人说史毕尔由于酒醉 毙了一个自己排的人
You're kidding.
你开玩笑吧?
That's unbelievable.
不可思议
Yeah, and there's another one about him giving cigarettes...
对 还有一个是有关于他先拿烟...
...to 20 German POWs before killing them.
给20个德军战俘抽 然后把他们全杀了
- He shot 20 POWs? - Actually, I heard it was more like 30.
- 他杀了20个战俘? - 事实上我听到的是约有30个
- Christenson. - Lieutenant Speirs.
- 克里斯登生! - 史毕尔中尉
- I got the name right, didn't I, Christenson? - Yes, sir.
- 我没把你名字叫错吧 克里斯登生? - 是 长官
What are you men doing out here?
你们在这里做什么?
We're watching the line, sir.
我们在看守战线 长官
Keep up the good work. You might wanna reinforce your cover.
继续努力 或许你们该加强掩体
Lieutenant Dike said not even to bother. That we're only gonna be here one day.
戴克中尉说不用麻烦了 说只会在此待一天
Lieutenant Dike said that?
戴克中尉这么说的?
Then forget what I said.
别管我说的了
Carry on.
继续
Anyone care for a smoke?
有人要来根烟吗?
You?
你要吗?
Late in the afternoon on January 3...
1月3日下午
...we returned to our old position in the woods overlooking Foy.
我们回到俯瞰佛伊的森林旧阵地里
You gotta be fucking kidding me.
谁给我开这种玩笑
Someone's gonna die. Someone's gonna fucking die.
有人该去死了
Guarnere, look at this shit!
葛奈瑞 你看看这团屎!
One of those 1st Battalion fuckers took a dump in my foxhole.
第一营的哪个混蛋在我的散兵坑里拉屎
I think they shit in everyone's foxhole, Joe.
我想他们在每个人的坑里都拉了屎 乔
I don't think they wanted to spend much time above ground.
我想他们都不愿意在地面上待太久
While we were in the Bois Jacques...
当我们在波扎克时
...the Germans had been shelling our old position.
德军对我们的旧阵地进行炮轰
There were signs of tree bursts everywhere.
到处都有树被炸断的景象
That got our attention.
那引起了我们的注意
Light and noise discipline.
禁声禁光 严守纪律
We're getting close.
我们越来越靠近了
Looking across the field at Foy, I could see enemy troops.
从旷野向佛伊望去 我可以看见敌军
I still couldn't see their artillery, but I knew it was down there.
但还是看不见他们的大炮 可我知道它就在那里
Looks like the Krauts have been pounding this area with pretty big stuff, 88s.
看来德军已经用他们的88毫米炮炸过这个区域了
I'd say they got this whole stretch of the line targeted.
我敢说他们已经标定了这条防线所有战壕
- They're not shelling now. - Maybe they've got a new target...
- 他们现在没有进行炮轰 - 也许他们找到了新目标
No, they're just waiting.
不 他们只是在等待
- For what? - For us to reoccupy the position.
- 等什么? - 等我们重新占领这个地方
Maybe we should fall back and dig in.
也许我们该撤到不同的地点再驻扎
No, it's our job to hold the line here.
不 我们的任务就是要守住这里
We've got pretty good foxholes. We just need to fortify the covers.
我们已经有挖好的散兵坑 只需要再加强掩体
- If they've got us targeted, maybe... - We hold the line here.
- 如果他们已瞄准我们了 也许... - 守住这里的防线
Sergeant Lipton's right.
李普军士长说得对
We're gonna strengthen our covers and we're gonna hang in.
我们要加强掩体撑下去
We're not gonna fall back.
我们不会撤退的
Right, Lieutenant?
对吧 连长?
- Right, Lieutenant? - Fine.
- 对吧 连长? - 很好!
You all take care of it.
你全权负责
I gotta go talk to Regiment.
我要去团部开会了
We'd better get moving. Yeah.
我们该出发了
- Here you go, Bill. - Thanks, Lip.
- 这个给你 比尔 - 谢谢 李普!
- I'll get you some more branches. - I'd appreciate that.
- 我再帮你弄些树枝 - 感激不尽!
Incoming!
敌炮射击!
Take cover!
找掩体!
Take cover! Come on, find some cover!
快隐蔽!
They got us zeroed!
他们瞄准我们了!
Find some cover, find a foxhole!
找掩体 找散兵坑!
Come on, take cover!
快点 找掩体!
Take cover!
找掩体
Come on, find some cover!
快点 快找掩体!
Shit.
可恶
For some reason, at that moment, in that half-finished foxhole...
不知何故 那一刻 在挖了一半的坑里 我脑海里想的
...all I could think about was the Fourth of July when I was a kid.
都是小时国庆日的景象
I loved to make my own firecrackers, cherry bombs, ladyfingers.
我喜欢自己做鞭炮 大龙炮 仙女棒
I loved to blow up dirt clods and pop bottles and the like.
我喜欢炸翻土块 还有炸玻璃瓶之类的东西
Looked forward to it all year long.
每年都期盼这一刻到来
What I saw that day was the most awesome...
我那天看到的是我有生以来
...and terrifying display of firepower I'd ever seen in my life.
最壮观与骇人的火力展示
Of course, I wouldn't have been laughing if I'd known what happened to Joe Toye.
当然若我知道乔托伊出了什么事 就笑不出来了
- Maybe we should see if anybody's hit. - Malark, that's what they want.
- 也许该看看有谁受伤 - 马拉其 这就是他们要的
The Krauts are trying to draw us out in the open.
德军就是要把我们引到空旷地
Stay in your foxholes. Stay in your foxholes!
留在散兵坑里! 留在你的散兵坑里!
Are you okay, can you walk? Come on, find a foxhole, come on.
你还好吗? 还能走吗? 快点 找个散兵坑
I gotta get up.
我得站起来...
I need my helmet.
我要我的钢盔...
I need help!
我需要帮忙!
- You hear that? - Is that Joe?
- 你听到了吗? - 那是乔吗?
Help!
救命!
Yeah, I think that's Joe.
对 我想是乔
Stay.
等着
Stay down!
姿势放低!
Stay in your foxholes!
留在你的散兵坑里!
Help!
救命!
Help, anyone there?
帮帮我 附近有人吗?
- Jesus. - I gotta get up.
- 老天 - 我得站起来
I gotta get up.
我得...站起来
Shit.
狗屎
Come on, Joe. Come on, buddy.
加油 乔
Come on, pal.
加油 老友
You said you'd get back to the States before me.
你说过你要比我早回美国的
You ain't going anywhere, you're all right.
你哪里都不会去 你会没事的
I gotta get my helmet.
我得拿我的钢盔
- Forget it. - I gotta get my helmet.
- 别管它了 乔 - 我得拿我的钢盔
Anyone there?
附近有人吗?
- Hang on. - Help!
- 撑下去 - 救命!
- Who's that? - It's Heff.
- 那是谁? - 是赫夫朗贝比
Come on, get me out of here, Lip.
救我出来 李普
Come on.
加油
I got you.
我扶住你了
Come on, Joe, I got you.
加油 乔 我扶住你了
Come on, Joe.
加油 乔
Hang on.
撑着点
Are you okay? Come on.
你还好吗?
Think I overdid it on the cover for my foxhole?
我的散兵坑是不是掩蔽过度了?
Incoming!
敌炮射击!
Take cover!
找掩体!
Come on!
快点!
Hurry up, Guarno, you're gonna get bombed!
葛奈瑞 你会被炸到 快点!
Come on! Move it, Bill!
比尔 快点!
Come on, Joe.
加油 乔
Hold on, I'll be there, I'm gonna help you.
撑着 我要过去了 我要来帮你们了
No!
不!
Medic!
医护兵!
During the second barrage, I wasn't laughing anymore.
在第二轮的炮击中 我再也笑不出来了
Lip!
李普?
Are you okay?
你还好吗?
Stay down!
姿势放低!
You stay down!
你姿势放低!
First Sergeant Lipton?
李普军士长?
You get things organized here.
这里交给你指挥
I'm gonna go for help.
我去请求支援
What the fuck?
搞什么鬼?
- Lip, where the fuck's he going? - I don't know.
- 李普 他要去哪? - 我不知道
Get Battalion on the line. Tell them to notify BAS.
听着 跟营部取得联系 叫他们通知营部参谋
Battalion's up, Lip.
知道了 李普!
Medic!
医护兵!
Stay ready.
保持待命
Sons of bitches might be trying to come through.
够娘养的敌军可能会试着突破我们
- You okay, One Lung? - Sergeant!
- 你还好吗? 马拉其? - 军士长!
- How you doing, Popeye? - 100 percent ready to kill Germans, Lip.
- 你还好吗 普派? - 准备好要杀德国人了 李普
Okay, Joe.
好了 乔
- Doc, what can I do? - Hold this.
- 医生 我能做些什么吗? - 抓住这里
You got a smoke?
你有烟吗?
Jesus, what's a guy gotta do to get killed around here?
在这里 要怎样才死得了?
Bill, you're going first.
比尔 你先走
- Whatever you say, Doc, whatever you say. - Over here, take this man.
- 都听你的 医生 - 在这里 把他拾走
- Lip, they got old Guarnere this time. - We got you, soldier.
- 李普 这次老葛中弹了 - 我们会照顾你的 阿兵哥
Just lie back.
你向后躺好
Take it easy. I told you I'd beat you back to the States.
放松点 乔 我说过会比你先回美国的
Lip.
嘿 李普
How's Buck?
巴克还好吗?
Luz, how's Buck?
鲁兹 巴克还好吗?
He's fine.
他没事
- You sure? - Yes, he's fine.
- 你确定? - 是 他没事...
I think you should probably go talk to him now.
我想你现在最好去和他谈谈?
All right.
好的
Some say Buck changed after he was shot in Holland.
有人说巴克在荷兰中弹后变了
Maybe.
也许吧...
I know something happened to him when he saw Toye and Guarnere on the ground.
可我认为 当他看到托伊跟葛奈瑞倒地后对他影响很大
On the report it said Compton was being taken off the line because of trench foot.
在报告上写着康普顿是因严重的战壕脚才离开战线
Didn't say anything about him losing his friends.
没有提到他失去挚友一事
Buck was a great combat leader.
巴克是个很好的战斗领导
He was wounded in Normandy, and again in Holland.
他在诺曼第受伤 第二次是在荷兰
He received the Silver Star for his part in taking out those German guns on D-day.
因为在D日协助摧毁德军大炮而获颁银星勋章
He took everything the Krauts could throw at him time and again.
他能承受德军所有炮火的摧残
Lieutenant Compton?
康普顿中尉?
"UCLA did not make the Rose Bowl this winter.
加大洛杉矶分校今年冬天没打进玫瑰杯足球赛
"Probably because you weren't there.
可能是因为你不在
"I'm sure you're teaching all of your young soldiers...
我相信 你在教导年轻士兵
"...the joy you have of the sport.
在运动中享受的乐趣
"Gosh, how we all know what an exciting young man you are...
我们都知道你是多么热情的青年
"...and how your heart and love..."
还有你的心跟爱...
I guess he just couldn't take seeing his friends Toye and Guarnere torn up like that.
我想他就是无法接受好友托伊跟葛奈瑞受到摧残
No one ever thought any less of him for it.
没有人因为他哭而看轻他
Hey Bull.
大牛
With Buck off the line, there was no longer any possible alternative to Dike.
由于巴克退下战线 再也没有替换戴克的可能
At least none we could see.
至少我们还看不到可能
Thanks.
谢了
Muck.
嘿 穆克
- Muck. - Yes, Sergeant?
- 穆克! - 什么事 军士长?
I'm looking for Lieutenant Dike.
我在找戴克连长
- We were stuck with Dike. - He's over there
- 我们甩不掉戴克了 - 他在那里
And he was off taking a walk.
而他正外出散步
Sure thing.
当然
Lightning Six, kidnap.
营部呼叫闪电六号
Yes, sir. We've cleared all the green area between...
是 长官 我们已清除这附近所有绿色区域
We'd cleared the woods east of Foy.
我们要扫荡佛伊东边森林区
So, a few days later, E Company and the rest of the 506...
几天后Ｅ连及其他506团兄弟
...cleared the woods west of Foy.
扫荡佛伊西边森林
There was little resistance.
仅遇到小规模抵抗
You fellas know I got no reason to bullshit you, right?
你们知道我没理由骗你们 对吧?
Look, I'm not gonna bullshit you. This is what I saw.
听着 我不会骗你们 是我亲眼看见的
It was so unbelievable, you might not believe me.
真令人难以置信 你们可能不会相信我
So, you-know-who comes running up to Lipton.
你们知道那个人跑去找李普
He's got no helmet, no gear, no nothing.
他没戴头盔 没带装备 什么都没有
First Sergeant Lipton, you organize things here...
李普军士长 这里交给你指挥
...and I'm gonna go for help.
我去请求...支援
I need to go polish my oak leaf clusters.
我得去把我的校官徽擦亮
- Luz - That's really good.
- 鲁兹 - 学得真不错
- It's okay - Fellas.
- 还可以 - 伙计们
- Goodnight all. - Yeah, see you, Luz. - See you, Malark.
- 大家晚安! - 再见 鲁兹! - 再见 马拉其!
- What can I do for you, Sarge? - Two things, first, great impression of Dike.
- 什么事 军士长? - 两件事 第一 你对戴克的描述很传神
You think so? I thought it was a little off.
我觉得有点过火
No, you got it pretty good. Second, don't do it any more.
不 你表演得很好 第二 别再这么做了
Especially the part about what he said to me.
特别是他跟我说了些什么这部分
It doesn't do anybody any good, okay?
对任何人都没好处
- Yeah, I got you. - All right.
- 好 我知道了 - 很好
Wise ass.
鬼灵精
Incoming!
敌炮射击
Luz!
鲁兹!
- Come on! - Hurry!
- 快走! - 快点!
- Stay down! - Come on!
- 趴下! - 快走!
Get in here! Come on!
快点进来!
- Come on! - Come on, Luz!
- 快点 - 鲁兹!
- Muck and Penkala! - What?
- 穆克和潘卡拉! - 什么?
Muck and Penkala got hit!
穆克和潘卡拉被炸中了!
Medic!
医护兵!
It's my shoulder. Come on, get up!
我的肩膀 快站起来!
Stay down till you get the all clear.
趴下 直到炮击停止
- Thought you didn't smoke. - I don't.
- 我以为你不抽烟的 - 我是不抽
The shell that hit the foxhole Luz and I were in was a dud.
掉进我和鲁兹散兵坑里的是颗未爆弹
The one that hit Muck and Penkala's foxhole wasn't.
掉进穆克和潘卡拉的那颗不是
That's just the way it was.
命运就是这样
Muck and Penkala were good men.
穆克和潘卡拉都是好人
Their death hit Malarkey the hardest.
他们的死打击马拉其最深
Malarkey's best friends in the Company had been Compton, Muck, and Penkala.
马拉其在连上的死党是康普顿、穆克和潘卡拉
In less than a week, he'd seen two of them die.
不到一个星期他就看到其中两位阵亡
- What's the word? - The men on the line are okay.
- 情况如何? - 在战线上的兄弟还好
Food has just been resupplied. We're in good shape.
食物刚刚补给过来 我们的状况良好
Okay, we'll just hunker down. We might get some relief soon.
好 我们就保持低姿势 可能很快就可以休息了
- Okay? - All right.
- 好吗? - 行 就这样
All right.
就这样
Later that day, we were back in our old position overlooking Foy.
当晚我们回到能俯瞰佛伊的森林旧阵地里
We were all worried about Malarkey.
我们都很担心马拉其
Malark.
马拉其
Didn't I hear you say you wanted to bring a Luger home for your kid brother?
我是不是听你说你要带把鲁格枪回家给弟弟?
Yeah.
对
Why don't you...
那么...
Why don't you give him that?
你就给他这把吧
- It's Hoob's, right? - Yeah.
- 这是胡伯勒的 对吗? - 对!
Yeah, I was gonna get rid of it but I...
我本来想把它丢了 可是我...
I don't know.
我不知道
Listen...
听着...
...Captain Winters was wondering if you wanted to go back to battalion and...
温特斯上尉在想 不知道你愿不愿意回营部
...work as his runner for a few days.
当几天他的传令?
Tell him thanks, I'm gonna stay here.
跟他说谢谢 我要留在这里
Look, why don't you at least come back for an hour or so.
这样吧 你至少回去一小时
Say goodbye to Buck. I'm sure it'll mean a lot to him.
对巴克说再见 我相信这对他意义重大
All right.
好吧
You be careful with that.
你带着那把枪小心点
Getting even 50 yards back from the line...
就算只从前线退下来50码
...just for an hour or two could make a big difference in a soldier's state of mind.
仅仅一两个小时 对军人心理状态而言 也有很大差别
The morning after the shelling that killed Muck and Penkala...
在穆克跟潘卡拉被炸死的隔天早上
...I saw a soldier try to dig a foxhole with his bare hands.
我看到一位士兵想徒手挖散兵坑
Private.
二等兵
Didn't notice he'd torn off his fingernails.
他没注意到所有指甲都挖断了
I got him out of there quickly.
我很快把他带离那里
Not for his sake, but for ours.
不是为了他 而是为了我们
Fear is poison in combat.
恐惧在战斗中是毒药
It's something we all felt, but you just didn't show it.
它是我们都感觉到却不表现出来
You can't.
你无法表现
It's destructive and it's contagious.
它具毁灭性 也有传染性
- Told you I'd get you started. - We got a bleeder here.
- 我说过有办法让你振作起来... - 这有人流血不止
Buck was never the same after seeing Toye and Guarnere get hit that day.
巴克在看到托伊跟葛奈瑞重创后 已经变了个人
I guess he just needed some time away from it all.
我想他需要些时间远离这一切
The barrages on January 3, and the shelling on January 9...
1月3日及9日的炮击
...marked the low point in the war for many of the men in E Company.
是大多Ｅ连兄弟参战后的最低潮
Even then, very few actually broke.
就算在当时 也很少人真正崩溃
I knew the terror of those shellings and the pressure we'd been under...
但我知道炮击的恐惧和巴斯通以来所累积的压力
...since we got to Bastogne could take their toll in other ways.
可能会从别的管道爆发
I was afraid the men would lose focus, suffer a drop in morale.
我很担心兄弟们无法专心 士气变得低落
And that was dangerous, especially in combat.
这是很危险的事 特别是在作战中
More of which lay in store for us.
而我们还有无数战斗要面对
Perconte.
派康提
We'd cleared the woods east and west of Foy.
我们已清除佛伊东边与西边的森林
Now it was time for the inevitable assault on Foy, itself.
现在对佛伊的攻击 是在所难免了
Frankly, I was dreading it.
老实说 我很害怕
I always knew the E Company men who trained at Toccoa...
我一直都知道从塔可亚
...wouldn't survive the war unscathed...
出来的Ｅ连兄弟不会毫发无伤
...but now I was beginning to wonder if any of us were gonna make it through at all.
可我现在开始怀疑 我们还有人能存活下去
E Company would lead the attack.
Ｅ连将带头攻击
The problem was, at least in my estimation...
问题是 至少在我看来
...E Company still did not have a leader.
Ｅ连依然没有领导者
The night before the attack, I did something as First Sergeant...
在进攻的前一晚 我以军士长身分
...I would never have imagined myself doing.
做了件我从未想象自己会做的事
Lip.
李普...
- Didn't figure you for a smoking man. - Neither did I.
- 没想到你会抽烟 - 我也没想到
D Company, Lieutenant Speirs, patrol order.
给Ｄ连史毕尔中尉的巡逻命令
So?
怎样?
We've been watching Foy all day, sir, not much activity.
我们整天盯着佛伊 长官 没什么动静
- Want a coffee? - No, thank you, sir.
- 来点咖啡吗? - 不用 谢谢长官
- How's Easy's status? - The men are good, sir, they're prepared.
- Ｅ连状况如何? - 兄弟们都好 长官 都准备好了
I'm gonna be leading 2nd Platoon, tomorrow.
我明天会带领第二排
They're probably the weakest after losing Toye...
虽然在失去了托伊 葛奈瑞
...and Guarnere, and Muck, and Penkala.
穆克和潘卡拉后可能心情低落
But all in all, I have every confidence in the men, sir.
但就整体而言 我对他们还是有信心 长官
Good.
很好
But, on the other hand, I have no confidence in our CO, sir.
可另一方面 我对我们的连长没信心
Lieutenant Dike is an empty uniform, Captain.
戴克中尉只是个穿着制服的空壳
He's just...
他只是...
He's not there, sir.
他根本不存在
He's gonna be there tomorrow.
他明天会在的
Yes, sir, I understand he will be there physically.
是 长官 我知道他明天会出现
But tomorrow's gonna be the real deal...
可是明天将是场硬仗
...and he's gonna have to lead those men.
而他必须带领那些兄弟
He's gonna have to make decisions, sir, and I...
他需要做决定 长官 而我
I gotta tell you, sir, I think he's gonna get a lot of Easy Company men killed.
我得告诉您 长官 我觉得他会害死很多Ｅ连兄弟
- Thank you, Sergeant, that'll be all. - Yes, sir.
- 谢谢你 军士长 就这样 - 是 长官
I said what I had to say. There was nothing Winters could do.
我说了我该说的 温特斯也没有办法
He couldn't very well remove a company CO.
他不能就这样撤换一位连长
Especially a well-connected one...
特别是有后台的连长
...because of the misgivings of a company first sergeant.
只因为一位军士长的疑虑
There's an eighth of a mile of open field to cross before we get down here into Foy.
我们在进入佛伊前要通过大约1/8里的旷野
There's little cover, so move quickly.
遮掩物很少 所以你们得快速移动
There's two sections of light machine guns, either end.
我在两端部署了两个轻机枪班
They'll give you covering fire.
他们会提供你掩护火力
3rd Battalion will come from the east led by I Company.
第三营会由Ｉ连带领 从东推进
That should cause distraction.
应该会分散德军注意力
D Company will be in reserve but we shouldn't need them.
Ｄ连为预备队 但是我们应该用不着
You gotta move in there fast.
重点是你要快速前进
Get in there before they can bring their mortars and artillery down on you.
在他们准备迫击炮及炮兵对付你之前冲过去
- Clear? - Clear.
- 清楚吗? - 清楚
I'm relying on you. Get it done.
全指望你了 把它完成
- Covering fire! - Let's go! Keep it moving!
- 掩护射击! - 保持前进!
Suppressing fire!
压制火力!
Keep moving! Move!
保持前进!
Let's go!
前进!
Suppressing fire! Fire!
压制火力! 射击!
Keep them tight, Shames.
叫他们靠紧一点 宣姆士
Keep moving. Come on.
继续前进 快点
Krauts in the open!
德军在空地!
- Keep moving! - Three inside!
- 继续前进! - 里面三个!
Wait a minute, where's Foley?
等一下 佛利在哪里?
Randleman!
蓝道曼!
Liebgott.
李高特
Where the hell is 1st Platoon?
第一排哪儿去了?
- Hold up! - Keep moving!
- 停止前进! - 继续前进!
Easy Company, hold up!
Ｅ连 停止前进
2nd Platoon, hold up!
第二排 停下来!
- Will you move! - Get me Foley on the radio.
- 给我前进! - 叫佛利来听无线电
- Get out of there! Move! - Sir, I think we should take cover.
- 别躲在那 前进! - 长官 我想我们该找掩体
Find some cover!
找掩体!
- Find some cover! - What?
- 快找掩体! - 什么?
Stay down!
卧倒!
- Easy Red, Easy Red. Easy Six. Over. - Six, Easy Red, go ahead.
- 红色Ｅ连 6号呼叫 完毕 - 6号 这是红色Ｅ连 请说
Easy Red, Easy Red, stand by for the Six.
红色Ｅ连 6号请你待命
Foley, you get back here where I can see you, goddamn it!
佛利! 你给我回到我看得到你的地方 该死!
1st Platoon, hold up. Take cover! Martin.
第一排 停止前进 找掩体! 马丁
Come on, soldier, with me. With you, sir.
跟我来 我跟着你 长官
Fire!
开火!
Fall back!
撤退!
- Take cover! - Goddamn it.
- 找掩体! - 可恶!
Go forward!
前进!
- Herron, on me. - Move back.
- 赫朗 跟我走 - 住回走!
- Stay on my ass. - Hold fast, 2nd Platoon.
- 跟在我后面 - 第二排待命
- Follow Lipton! Take cover! - What are we doing, Lieutenant?
- 跟着李普! 找掩体! - 我们在做什么 连长?
- Why are we stopped? - Fall back!
- 我们为什么停下来? - 撤退!
Roger, kidnap.
知道了 营部
- Standby to Six, - Lieutenant, what's the plan?
- 6号待命... - 连长 你计划如何?
I don't know!
我不知道!
You'd better get Dike on that radio to me now.
你最好快点叫戴克听无线电
Lieutenant, what's the plan?
连长 你计划如何?
- Captain Winters, sir. - What's the plan?
- 温特斯上尉找你 - 长官 给我们一个计划
Okay, Foley. Foley, you take your men...
佛利 你带你的兄弟...
...on a flanking mission around the village...
从侧翼绕过村落
...and attack it from the rear.
从后面攻击他们
Dike, we cannot stay here!
戴克 我们不能留在这里!
You want 1st Platoon to attack the village, by itself?
你要第一排绕过去 单独攻击这个村庄?
We will provide suppressing fire.
我们会提供你压制火力
We're gonna be alone out there, Lieutenant.
我们在那边会势单力薄 连长
We will provide suppressing fire!
我们会提供压制火力!
Get going forward!
继续向前进!
You need to talk to Captain Winters, sir.
你必须回复温特斯上尉 长官
Sir, okay, here it is.
长官 命令是这样
We go on a flanking run in the back of the village and we attack from the rear.
我们从侧翼绕过村落 从后面攻击
Ramirez, two guys, take them, go. Find some cover behind the stable.
蓝姆雷兹 你带两人去 在马厩后面找掩体
Go!
走!
- Shit! - Jesus Christ.
- 妈的! - 天啊
Webb, move up, find cover!
韦伯 快走 找掩体!
Suppressing fire, now!
压制火力 射击!
Perconte! I got you.
派康提! 我抓住你了
Give me some cover!
替我掩护
How you doing, Perconte?
你还好吗 派康提?
They shot me in my ass, Martin.
他们打中我的屁股 马丁
- You're all right, stay down! - I think we lost five men.
- 你没事的 躺下! - 我想我们失去了五位兄弟
Can you locate? The building with the caved-in roof.
你能找到他们吗? 在那栋有塌陷屋顶的房子
The building with the caved-in roof.
对 那栋有塌陷屋顶的房子
Sir, we are sitting ducks here.
长官 我们这是坐以待毙
We have to keep moving!
我们得继续前进!
You've got to keep moving!
你们得继续前进!
Dick! Captain Winters. Goddamn it, you do not go out there.
迪克! 温特斯上尉 可恶 你别出去!
You're the Battalion Commander, now get back here!
你是营长 快回来!
Dick, I understand your attachment to Easy Company...
我了解你对Ｅ连的感情
Speirs, get yourself over here!
史毕尔 你快过来
Get out there and relieve Dike and take that attack on in.
你去那里接替戴克 把攻击任务继续进行
Webb, fall back, you're too exposed.
韦伯 向后退 你太明显了
Come on, Webb, let's go, kid.
走 韦伯
- Hang on, Perco. - Fire!
- 撑着点 派康提 - 射击!
Lieutenant, what are we doing?
中尉 我们该怎么办?
I'm taking over. First Sergeant Lipton.
我来接管 李普军士长!
What have we got?
现在情况如何?
Sir, most of the Company is spread out here.
长官 连上大致散布在此
1st platoon tried an end around but they're stretched out, pinned by a sniper.
第一排尝试着绕道攻击 可是被狙击手打散了
I believe he's there at the caved-in roof.
我相信他藏在那栋有塌陷屋顶的屋子里
Destroy that building with mortars and grenade launchers.
用手榴弹和迫击炮消灭他们
Then, I want 1st to go in, forget going around.
然后 第一排直接攻入 别再绕道
- Everybody else, follow me. - Yes, sir.
- 其他人跟着我 - 是 长官
Thank God.
谢天谢地!
All right, 3rd Platoon, let's go!
第三排 我们走!
All right, you heard the word, 2nd Platoon, on the CO!
你们听到了 第二排跟着史毕尔连长走!
- Sergeant Alley! - Got it, Sarge.
- 艾利中士! - 知道了 军士长
Okay, 1st Platoon, move out!
好 第一排前进!
On your feet, 2nd Platoon. Move out!
第二排起立 出发!
Get on your goddamn feet.
快站起来
Come on!
快点!
Come on, Luz, let's get the bastards.
鲁兹 我们去痛宰那些狗娘养的!
Fire!
开火!
Come on, move out!
快点 出发了!
- Fire! - Take cover!
- 开火! - 找掩体!
Fire!
开火!
- Go! - Go on, come on.
- 快走! - 快点
Take the cart out!
歼灭那辆车!
Fire!
开火!
Lipton.
李普
Street fight, Item. Easy Six, over.
Ｉ连本部 Ｅ连6号呼叫 完毕
- What do you see, Lipton? - Armor and infantry, a lot of infantry.
- 你看到什么 李普? - 装甲车、步兵 很多步兵
I Company's should be on the other side of town.
Ｉ连应该在小镇另一头 你看到他们的踪迹吗?
Do you see any sign of them?
有什么信号吗?
- Radio, anything? - No, sir.
- 无线电有消息吗? - 没有 长官
Sir, I think they're gonna pull back.
长官 我想他们要撤退了
We don't connect with I, they'll escape.
若联系不上Ｉ连 他们就要逃走了
- That's right, wait here. - Item, Item. Easy Six.
- 没错 在这等着 - Ｉ连 Ｅ连6号呼叫
What the hell?
搞什么?
At first, the Germans didn't shoot at him.
开始德军并未向他射击
I think they couldn't quite believe what they were seeing.
我想他们不太敢相信他们所看到的
But that wasn't the really astounding thing.
可是那并不是最令人吃惊的事
The astounding thing was that after he hooked up with I Company...
令人吃惊的是 在他和Ｉ连接头后
...he came back.
他回来了
We took over 100 German prisoners.
我们抓获超过100名德军战俘
After that it was mostly clean up.
该镇也扫荡得差不多了
Let's go, move it, move it! Take them down to the barn.
我们走 快点! 带他们去谷仓
Sit down.
坐下
Sniper!
狙击手
Take cover!
找掩体!
Come on.
快点
Where is he?
他在哪里?
Shit, I can't see him.
可恶! 我看不到他
Second floor, building on the right.
右边建筑 二楼
Don't miss, Shifty. Now!
别打偏了 西福弟 开始!
Over here. I need help over here. Hey, can you guys get over here and help?
快来 我这里需要帮忙
Mellet, Herron, Sowosko, and Ken Webb were killed by a sniper.
梅略特、赫朗、索沃斯科、肯韦伯都被狙击手射杀了
There would've been more if it hadn't been for Shifty Powers.
要不是西福弟鲍尔斯 可能还会有更多伤亡
- You hit bad, Perconte? - Beautiful wound, Lip.
- 伤得严重吗 派康提? - 很漂亮的伤 李普
They shot me right through my ass.
他们打穿了我的屁股
- You hang tough. - Sarge.
- 勇敢撑下去 - 军士长
- Yeah? - Is it true about Dike?
- 哦 - 戴克的事是真的吗?
Yeah.
是的
Thank God for small mercies?
谢谢老天爷的小慈悲
We'd been looking down at Foy...
我们一个月来 一直在鸟瞰佛伊
...for the better part of a month, knowing that's where we had to go.
等待进攻最佳时机 心里明白那是我们最后必须攻下的
It was a great relief to have done it.
任务完成后 我们如释重负
A lot of the men thought once we'd taken Foy they'd get off the line...
我猜很多人以为 在攻下佛伊之后会让我们从前线退下
...ship us back to Mourmelon for a breather.
送我们回莫米朗喘口气
But that wasn't to be.
可是结果并非如此
Two days later, we took Noville, and after that, Rachamps.
两天后 我们攻下诺维尔 又占领拉千普
We spent our night in Rachamps, in a convent.
我们在拉千普的一个修道院过夜
It was the first time we'd spent a night indoors in a month.
那是我们一个月以来首次在室内过夜
The sisters there brought in their choir to sing for us.
院内的修女为我们唱圣歌
It was heaven.
有如在天堂般
The mood of the men was relaxed.
兄弟们的心情都放松了
We were finally being relieved and would soon be in Mourmelon.
我们终于被替换 并很快地要回莫米朗
Of course, in the morning we found out Mourmelon would have to wait.
当然 在早上我们发现 莫米朗还得再等一等
Hitler had launched a counteroffensive in Alsace...
希特勒在亚尔萨斯发动一波反攻
...and we were bound for the town of Hagenau to help hold the line.
而我们被派前住镇守哈根努
But at least for that night we didn't know it yet.
可至少当晚我们还不知道
That night we were okay.
那晚我们都很好
I spent that night trying to come up with a roster...
那晚我花了点时间 尝试着算一算
...for the Company, to see who we had left.
我们连上已经失去的兄弟
We'd come into Belgium with 121 men and officers...
我们在进入比利时的时候 有121名官兵
...plus 24 replacements.
加上24名补充兵
That's 145 total. We were going out with 63.
总共是145人 出来时只剩下63人
Guarnere was badly wounded and Hoobler died accidentally.
葛奈瑞受到重创 而胡伯勒死于意外
Joe Toye had lost his leg.
乔托伊少了一条腿
Among the dead were Herron, Mellet...
死亡的有赫朗 梅略特
...Sowosko, Kenneth Webb, Harold Webb...
索沃斯科 肯韦伯 哈洛韦伯
...Alex Penkala, and Skip Muck.
艾力克斯、潘卡拉以及史基普穆克
Our month in Belgium cost us one good officer, Buck Compton.
在比利时那个月 我们失去一位好军官——巴克.康普顿
And one bad one, Norman Dike.
以及一位烂军官——诺曼.戴克
But we gained a good one in the end, so I guess we came out ahead.
可最后得到一位好军官 所以还是有所收获的
What is it?
怎么了?
Nothing.
没什么
I'd better get back to Battalion before they disappear.
我最好在他们消失前回去营部
- You wanna ask me, don't you? - Ask you what, sir?
- 你有事要问我 是吗? - 问你什么 长官
You wanna know if they're true or not, the stories about me.
你想要知道有关我的故事到底是真是假
Did you ever notice with stories like that...
你注意过吗 这种故事
...everyone says they heard it from someone who was there...
每个人都说是从在现场的人那里听来的
...but then when you ask that person...
可是当你去问那个人
...they say they heard it from someone who was there.
他又会说他是从另一个在现场的人听来
It's nothing new, really.
这没什么稀奇的
I bet if you went back 2,000 years, you'd hear a couple of centurions...
我敢说若你回到2000年前 你会看到一群罗马战士
...yakking about how Tercius lopped off the heads of some Carthaginian prisoners.
讨论特西斯是如何将迦太基战俘们的头砍下
Maybe they kept talking about it because they never heard Tercius deny it.
也许他们一直谈论 是因为特西斯从来没否认
Maybe because Tercius knew there was some value to the men...
或许特西斯认为有必要让人知道
...thinking he was the meanest, toughest, son of a bitch in the Roman legion.
他是罗马军团中最狠毒、最强悍的角色
Sir?
长官?
These men aren't really concerned about the stories.
这些兄弟并不真正在意这些故事
They're just glad to have you as our CO.
他们只是很高兴由你来当连长
They're happy to have a good leader again.
他们很高兴又有了好的领导者
From what I've heard, they've always had one.
就我听到的 他们一直都有一个好领导者
I've been told there's always been one man they could count on.
有人曾说他们一直都有一个人可以依赖
Led them in Bois Jacques, held them together...
带他们攻入波礼克
...when they were shelled in the woods.
在森林遭炮轰时 将他们凝聚一起
Every day he kept his spirits up, kept the men focused, gave them direction.
每天振奋士气 使兄弟们聚精会神 引导方向
All the things a good combat leader does.
全是一个好战斗领袖做的事
You don't have any idea who I'm talking about, do you?
你完全不知道我在说谁?
No, sir.
不知道 长官
Hell, it was you, First Sergeant.
就是你 军士长
Ever since Winters made Battalion, you've been the leader of Easy Company.
自从温特斯升为营长后 你就是Ｅ连的领袖
And you're not gonna be first sergeant much longer.
还有 你当军士长不会太久了
Sir?
长官?
Winters put in for a Battlefield Commission and Sink approved on your behalf.
温特斯呈上一份战地委任书 辛克接受核准了
You should get the official nod in a few days.
几天内应该就会正式发布
Congratulations, Lieutenant.
恭喜你 少尉
Look, it's 1st Battalion.
你看 是第一营
What do you want?
什么事?
Yeah, thanks for crapping in our foxholes, you shitheads.
谢谢你们在我们的散兵坑里大便 猪头!
- It's our pleasure. - Enjoy the walk, boys.
- 是我们的荣幸 - 好好走吧 小子们
There they go, Easy Company.
Ｅ连又要上路